博物馆惊魂夜2
永久保存-联邦档案室
假设这是你家，没电没灯
What if this was your house?
Power's out. Lights are dead.
小朋友在床上大哭特哭
Your little ones in their bunk bed
down the hall, crying out...
爸！妈！快来啊，我好怕
Mommy! Daddy! Come quick! I'm scared!
-你得赶快过去
-来了，爸爸来了
-You need to get there, and fast.
-Coming, honey! Daddy's coming!
你需要武器
但首先你需要手电筒
You'll need a weapon.
But first, you'll need a flashlight.
可是黑得要命
But you're in the dark!
What are you gonna do?
要怎么找？我告诉你
How are you gonna find it?
l'll tell you how.
发光手电筒
The GIow-in-the-Dark FIashIight!
没错，各位
我是达理小发明的赖瑞达理
That's right, foIks!
I'm Larry DaIey of DaIey Devices,
本节目
and we're gonna spend
the next paid-programing bIock
要震撼你的世界
rocking your worId.
我请了一个朋友一起来
欢迎拳王乔治佛曼
And I brought aIong a friend to do it.
George Foreman, Iadies and gentIemen!
赖瑞，太好了
各位，赖瑞很棒吧？
Fantastic, Larry, fantastic!
Isn't he fantastic, America?
不过说真的
But, seriousIy, isn't it true
that just two years ago,
你两年前还是博物馆的夜班警卫？
you were working as a night guard
at some dusty museum?
对，你是两次世界重量级冠军
That is true, two-time worId
heavyweight champ George Foreman.
我只是拿手电筒作梦的路人甲
I was just a reguIar Joe
with a fIashIight and a dream.
你是说路人赖瑞吗？
You mean a reguIar Larry.
不过这可不是闹的
你是达理小发明的总裁
But what's no joke is
you're CEO of DaIey Devices,
你发明了重要的超大狗骨头
creator of such indispensabIe items
as the Super Big Dog Bone!
-你喜欢那个b品吗？
-丢不掉钥匙圈
-You Iike that one?
-The UnIosabIe Key Ring!
大家很熟悉的b品
Oh, yeah, that IittIe chestnut!
而现在你有了新的突破
大家跟我一起说出来
And now your Iatest breakthrough...
Say it with me, America !
发光手电筒
The GIow-in-the-Dark FIashIight!
达理小发明为您解决家庭危机
Whatever the househoId crisis,
this is DaIey Devices. Can I heIp you?
把这还给史都华，他会乱算
Gina, give this back to Stewart.
I don't trust his math, okay?
-那家伙又打来了
-又打来？
-That guy caIIed again.
-Again?
小赖，大消息
我们要跟连锁商店谈
Lar! Huge news!
We got the WaI-Mart meeting.
-不会吧，什么时候？
-三天后
-No! When?
-Yeah. Three days.
我们有很多事要做
Okay, aII right.
We got a Iot of work to do.
这可是大型连锁商店耶
WeII, okay, did you just hear me
say ''WaI'' and ''Mart'' together?
我知道，超大的
Yeah! I know, it's huge.
所以你该开心一下
So just take a second
to be happy about it.
好，耶！
AII right.
你在取笑我
You're totaIIy making fun of me.
谈妥以后再庆祝吧
No, Iet's hoId off on the victory parade
tiII we cIose, okay?
没问题
You got it.
-他什么时候想见面？
-礼拜五早上十点
-And when does he want to meet?
-They want Friday morning, 10:00 a.m.
谈推进器电锯的事
Okay, then, you know what?
CanceI that pitch
先取消
for the eIectric saw thing
with the propeIIer, aII right?
-我想专心做这件事
-好
-I just want to focus on this.
-Okay.
-只做这件事
-我女儿的生日不办了
-Just this.
-My daughter's birthday, canceIed!
你回家吧，我会到很晚
You can go home.
I'm gonna be pretty Iate, okay.
好的，老板
Okay, boss.
自然历史博物馆
关闭整修
不好意思，擅闯的人
HeIIo! Excuse me!
Unauthorized personneI!
这可不是发达先生吗？
If it isn't our very own
Mr. Success Story.
又跑来怀旧吗？我几个月没看到你了
Come for one of your nostaIgia tours?
I haven't seen you for a few months.
我很忙，这里是怎么回事？
Yeah, I've been busy.
What's going on here?
他们所谓的进步
Progress, so they teII me.
未来，看哪，自然历史2.0版
The future.
BehoId, NaturaI History, version 2.0.
欢迎光临自然历史博物馆
历史在这里活了过来！
Welcome to The Museum of Natural
History, where history comes to life!
过来发问吧
Step up, ask your question.
然后轮到下一个男生或女生
Then let the next little boy or girl
have their turn.
好，你在哪里出生？
Okay, where were you born?
就在纽约20街
Right here in New York City,
on Twentieth Street.
1858年10月27日
October 27th,
the year of our Lord 1858.
扯个不停，历史啊、学习啊
BIah, bIah, bIah.
History, history. Learning, Iearning.
让美国儿童渐渐蜕变
Changing America, one chiId at a time.
太好了，你们要增加互动式展览？
That's great. So you're adding
some new interactive exhibits?
不是增加，是取代旧的展品
No, Mr. DaIey, not adding.
RepIacing the oId exhibits.
-它们要去哪？
-送走
-Where are they going?
-Away.
我们要拿掉实景展览、蜡像
We're getting rid of aII this junk.
The dioramas, the waxworks,
破旧的动物也是，比方这只瘦猴
even some of the shabbier animaIs,
Iike this scrawny IittIe monkey.
小心，它是卷尾猴
You shouId be carefuI. He's a capuchin.
它是猴子
It's a monkey.
卷尾猴是稀有品种，不只是猴子
He's a rare breed. He's a capuchin.
He's not just a monkey.
猴子就是猴子，这么仔细干嘛？
''Monkey'', then. I said ''monkey''.
Why be specific?
猴子都要丢了，不需要拉丁学名
When you're throwing away a monkey,
you don't need the Latin name.
你们是要把它丢掉还是送走？
Are you throwing him away
or are you moving him?
你是灵长类垃圾警察吗？
宝贝，算了吧
What are you, the Primate
Garbage PoIice? Let it go, baby.
-这是谁的主意？
-我啊
-Whose idea was this?
-Me, of course.
我跟董事会负责
I'm in charge. Me and the board.
主要是董事会的决定
MainIy the board.
总之，你干嘛在乎？
Anyway, why do you care?
大家喜欢这些东西
No, it's just that peopIe
Iove this stuff.
达理，大家喜欢跨出下一步
PeopIe, Mr. DaIey, Iove ''What's next?''
你应该最清楚，你离开了
You shouId know that. You Ieft.
我的情况变了，事业起飞
My situation changed.
My business took off...
你成功了
如果我是夜班警卫，我也会走
Yeah, you became a success.
So wouId I, if I was a night guard.
这些家伙要去哪里？
So where are these guys going?
放到联邦档案室保存
Deep storage. FederaI Archives.
-那在哪里？
-华府
-Where's that?
-Washington, D.C.
史密森尼博物馆
The Smithsonian.
我们一定有办法解决
There's got to be something
that we can do.
事情解决了
他们明天早上送走，就这样
It's done!
They Ieave tomorrow morning. It's over.
老朋友，你好吗？你想怎么样？
Hey, buddy, how you doing?
How you doing with aII this?
你想要里头的东西？
You want what's in here?
我有东西要给你吗？
你以为我有绳子？
You think I got something for you?
You think I got a IittIe rope?
你以为你比我强？
Think you're stronger than me, huh?
你就只有这么一点力气吗？
Is that aII you got, huh?
劳伦斯，小子，很高兴见到你
Lawrence! Good to see you, Iad!
泰迪，我也是
Yeah, you too, Teddy.
布鲁克林的守护者回来了
The Guardian of BrookIyn has returned!
麦菲跟我说情况了
Hey, Ahk. Look, McPhee toId me
what's going on around here.
-我完全不晓得
-对呀
-I had no idea.
-Indeed.
你上次来过后发生很多事情
A Iot has transpired, Lawrence, since
your Iast visit. One wouId say that...
-等我一下
-你身上有蟋蟀声
-Just...
-Cricket.
大歌星，帮个忙啊
Hey, Bocephus! LittIe heIp over here!
嘿
Hey.
嘿，你们好吗？
Hey, feIIas. How you doing?
大家看看是谁
WeII, Iookee here.
这自大的家伙
If it ain't
Mr. Big-in-the-Britches himseIf,
回来送我们了
come back just in time to see us off!
嘉地雅，我听说了
我不知道怎么会这样
Yeah, Jed, I heard. Look,
I don't even know how this happened.
对，这件事情超让人不解的
Yeah. Yeah, reaI mystery
how this happened.
说不定你手上的魔术盒有答案
Maybe the answer's on that magic
buzzing box there in your hand!
巨无霸，你不在这里才会发生这种事
You weren't here, Gigantor!
That's how it happened!
没啥好不解的
Ain't no mystery!
开放时间
The fact is, Larry, there's no one eIse
here to speak on our behaIf
没人替我们说话
during business hours.
一个都没有，笨笨
None, none, dum-dum.
各位，没关系
Hey, guys! It's okay!
我早上打给董事会
我现在有点份量了
I'II caII the board in the morning,
aII right? I got some puII now.
我来处理，我们不会有事的
I'II handIe this.
We're gonna be okay here.
我们？你听到白日梦先生的话了吗？
''We''? Did you hear that?
You hear Daydream Johnny?
谁跟你一体了
There ain't been a ''we'' ever since
you put us on the ''pay no mind'' Iist.
你不理我们了耶
And that's a coId pIace to be, boy.
赖瑞，能做的都做了
Larry, what's done is done.
连罗马的光荣也会告终
Even the gIory of Rome
had to come to an end.
你可以不要夸张地望向远方吗？
WouId you pIease not Iook dramaticaIIy
off into the middIe distance
让我感觉更糟
when you say that?
It makes me feeI worse.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're taIking about.
你在看哪里？我在这啊
Where are you Iooking?
Where are you Iooking? I'm over here.
看墙壁
Just a bit of waII.
说不定事情没那么糟
Look, guys, maybe it won't be so bad.
说得好
Yes, you make a good point.
我们说的可是史密森尼博物馆耶
But this is the Smithsonian
we're taIking about here.
德克斯，这你可不知道
Dexter, you don't know that.
巨无霸，你没搞清楚重点
我们要被运走
You're missing the point, Gigantor!
They're shipping us out!
我知道你想安慰我们
Larry, I know you're trying
to make us feeI better.
我看得出你有点不安
I can see that you're genuineIy
sIightIy bothered,
不过情况再也不一样了
but it's never going to be the same.
我们不会一起在这里了
AII of us here, together,
in this pIace.
史密森尼永远不会是我们的家
It ain't never gonna be home, boy.
嘉地雅，拜托
劳伦斯，大家都很感伤
Jedediah, pIease! Lawrence, these
are emotionaI times for aII of us.
但这是我们一家人最后一晚相处
But it is our Iast night as a famiIy,
我不希望大家自怨自艾
and I don't want to see it squandered
in seIf-pity.
谁要跟我去逛最后一次？
So who wiII join me for one finaI stroII
through these haIIowed haIIs?
-你想去散步吗？
-不想
-Do you want to go for a waIk?
-No.
我要自怨自艾
I'm just gonna
squander it in seIf-pity.
亲爱的，走吧
My dear, shaII we?
亲爱的，一路顺风
Safe journey, my Iove.
德克斯，需要帮忙吗？
Hey, Dexter, want some heIp there?
好了，大家别伤感情，好吗？
Hey, come on, man.
No hard feeIings, aII right?
不会有事的
It's gonna be fine.
劳伦斯，天快亮了
It's aImost dawn, Lawrence.
泰迪，你的箱子呢？
Yeah. So, where's your crate, Teddy?
劳伦斯，我不会去
I won't be making this journey,
Lawrence.
看来我、暴龙跟几个著名展品
It seems myseIf, Rexy,
and a few of the signature exhibits
暂时会留下来
wiII be staying here for now.
刻写板也会送走吗？
Without the tabIet?
事实上
In truth, Lawrence,
阿卡曼拉的刻写板会跟他留下来
Ahkmenrah's tabIet
wiII be remaining here with him.
什么？
What?
朋友，刻写板不跟他们一起送去
They're going without
the tabIet, my friend.
今晚恐怕是他们的最后一夜了
I'm afraid this night is their Iast.
你没告诉他们
You didn't teII them.
有时候撒点小谎
比隐瞒痛苦的事实高尚
Sometimes it's more nobIe to teII a
smaII Iie than deIiver a painfuI truth.
-你不会有事吧？
-我会尽力而为
-Are you gonna be okay?
-I shaII do my best.
谁知道呢
And who knows?
有时，大改变会带来更大的契机
Sometimes the greatest change
brings about even greater opportunity.
劳伦斯，看看你
Look at you, Lawrence.
你离开这里后，人生过得很精彩
You Ieft this pIace
and created quite a Iife for yourseIf.
我猜是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
朋友，不要猜
I shouId hope
you'd do more than guess, my friend.
你是工业大王，你呼风唤雨
You're a captain of industry.
The worId at your fingertips.
生活如意
It seems to me
you have everything you wanted.
是，我知道
Yeah, no, I know.
你才不知道
No, you don't. If I may, Iad,
请容我给你一点忠告
aIIow me to offer you
one piece of advice.
真正幸福的关键在于…
The key to happiness,
to true happiness, is...
等我一下
Hang on one sec. I just gotta...
我要处理日本的生意
I got this Japanese deaI.
我关机了，抱歉
No, okay, I'm turning this off.
I'm sorry.
幸福的关键是什么？
The key to happiness?
泰迪，再见了
I'II see you, Teddy.
自然历史博物馆
他们走了？你不能想办法吗？
So they're gone?
There's nothing you can do?
我希望可以，我什么都试了
I wish there was, man.
I'm teIIing you, I tried everything.
我去找麦菲谈，打给董事会
可是他们今天早上被送走了
I taIked to McPhee, I caIIed the board,
but they shipped them out this morning.
爸，你买了好多菜
This is a Iot of food, Dad.
我同事艾德要过来谈点事情
Yeah. Ed from work's gonna come by.
I thought I toId you.
不是跟你说了吗？
We just have to go over
a coupIe of IittIe work things.
-你今晚要工作
-我以前每天晚上都要工作
-So you're working tonight.
-I used to work every night, remember?
那是全世界最酷的工作
That was when you had
the cooIest job in the worId.
酷不能帮你买吉他之神6
Yeah, weII, ''cooI'' doesn't pay
for your Guitar God Vl or whatever.
-喂？
-巨无霸，是我啦，嘉地雅
-HeIIo?
-Gigantor! lt's me, Jedediah!
-停！停！
-阿嘉？
-Hold! Hold!
-Jed?
绝不投降！
Never surrender!
阿嘉，你是怎么拨电话的？
Jed, what are you...
How did you diaI the phone?
说来话长，那只泼猴偷了刻写板
Long story! That brazen IittIe monkey
stoIe the tabIet,
这下我们惨了！
and now we're in a worId of hurt, boy!
-怎么回事？
-卡曼拉！
-What's going on?
-Kahmunrah!
-卡曼拉？
-阿卡曼拉的哥哥，他在这里！
-Kahmunrah?
-Ahkmenrah's big brother! He's here!
-相信我，他很不友善！
-休想！
-And trust me, not a friendIy!
-Never!
重复，他很不友善！
I repeat, not a friendIy!
-那是阿提拉吗？
-不知道…
-Is that AttiIa, Jed?
-l don't know how much longer
-还要战多久，不！
-阿嘉，你还好吗？
-we can fight them off! No!
-Jed? Are you okay?
-放开我，救命啊！
-阿嘉
-Let go of me! Help!
-Hey, Jed.
-放开我，救命啊！
-阿嘉？
-Let go! No, you let go of me! Help!
-Jed?
怎么回事？
What was that about?
我不知道
I don't know.
走，我带你去你妈家
Here, come on.
Gonna drop you off at your mom's.
-爸，怎么了？
-我要过去了解
-What's going on, Dad?
-I'm gonna go find out.
麦菲说联邦档案室在史密森尼
Okay, buddy, McPhee said the
FederaI Archives are in the Smithsonian.
我到底要去哪里？
Where exactIy am I going?
爸，史密森尼有19个馆
That's the thing, Dad. The Smithsonian
is actuaIIy 19 different museums.
在国家广场上
They're Iaid out
around the NationaI MaII,
从国会大厦延伸到林肯纪念堂
from the CapitoI
to the LincoIn MemoriaI.
那里有很多超酷的东西
They got everything there.
There's actuaIIy some reaIIy cooI stuff.
尼其，专心点
档案室在哪一个馆里头？
Nicky, pIease focus.
Which museum are the Archives in?
是在底下，史密森尼底下整片都是
Not in, under. It Iooks Iike it runs
underneath the entire Smithsonian.
如果刻写板在那里…
So if Ahkmenrah's tabIet is
down there...
全世界最大的博物馆就复活了
The biggest museum in the worId
is coming aIive.
爸，你有什么计划？
What is exactly is your plan here, Dad?
-你放心吧
-你没计划，对不对？
-Don't worry about it.
-You have no pIan, do you?
我有深思熟虑的计划
Now, NichoIas, I have a very good,
highIy thought-out pIan.
-你没有计划
-好啦，我没有计划
-You have no pIan.
-Yes, I have no pIan.
我进去后打给你
I'II caII you when I'm in.
给你，谢谢
Here you go. Thanks.
航太博物馆
美国空军
欢迎莅临全世界最大的博物馆
WeIcome to the biggest museum
in the worId.
我知道，很刺激
I know, right? It's a trip.
天花板吊的这些飞机怎么样？超怪的
How about these pIanes dangIing
from the ceiIings, huh? Pretty weird.
你知道要怎么进联邦档案室吗？
Hi, excuse me. CouId you teII me
how to get to the FederaI Archives?
当然罗，只要当历史文物就行啦
Of course. Just be a historicaI document
worthy of storing for aII eternity.
开玩笑的啦，他不是文物
I'm kidding. He's not a document.
先生，抱歉，档案室在地下楼层
民众不能进去
I'm sorry, sir, the Archives are
underground, and they're a secure area.
真的不能进去吗？
好吧，谢谢
ReaIIy? Like, totaIIy secure?
Okay, thank you.
非员工请勿进入
爱因斯坦摇头公仔
各位先生女士
本馆即将在一小时后结束参观
Ladies and gentlemen,
the museum will be closing in one hour.
禁止进入-请出示证件
卡彭逃漏税被捕
卡曼拉之门-通往底下世界之门
卡曼拉
Kahmunrah.
嘿，你在干嘛？
Hey! What are you doing?
-禁止触摸
-我没有要摸
-No touching.
-No, I wasn't gonna touch it.
你有ITT
You're moving in with some I.T.T., bro.
-ITT？
-老兄，ITT就是“你想要摸”
-I.T.T.?
-That's ''Intent to Touch'', homey.
我没有
No, I wasn't.
You're not aIIowed to go over the...
-那你是要亲它吗？
-好，抱歉
-What, are you gonna kiss it?
-AII right, sorry.
你动手摸吧
Put your hand on it and touch it.
'Cause I stand there
我等你这种娘泡一整天了
and I wait aII day
for a IittIe girI Iike you to come in
拿做的美美的指甲去碰展品
and put her precious naiI-poIished naiIs
aII over the exhibits.
美国不是自由国家吗？
Sorry. Last time I checked, I thought
we Iived in a free country, so...
-我们不是
-不是吗？
-No, we don't.
-No?
不是，这是个“非礼勿碰”合众国
It's the United States of Don't Touch
That Thing Right in Front of You.
我总可以看吧
I just want to...
I'm aIIowed to Iook at it here, okay?
你摸摸看啊
See what happens when you touch it!
布兰登，你在威胁我吗？
So you're threatening me?
You're threatening me, Brandon?
-我叫布朗登
-什么？
-It's ''Brundon.''
-Excuse me?
-布朗登
-布朗登？
-''Brundon''!
-''Brundon''?
-布朗登
-''Brundon.''
你的名字拼错了吗？
What, did they run out of U's
on your namepIate maker?
你的笑话好冷喔
I don't know, did they run out of jokes
没笑话可说了吗？
at the interesting-joke store
that you shop at?
看起来是布兰登没错啊
Sorry, it Iooks Iike ''Brandon'', but...
我不是你的语言治疗师
这是布朗登！
I'm not here to be your
speech therapist. It's ''Brundon''!
-好吧，布朗登
-你没听过这名字吗？
-''Brundon.'' Okay...
-You never heard of the name before?
没听过“布朗登”
''Brundon''? No.
去查1984年最红的宝宝名字
是“布朗登”
Look up most popuIar baby names
in 1984. ''Brundon.''
好，布朗登，你在威胁我吗？
Okay. Are you threatening me, Brundon?
我不知道，娘泡王子，我有吗？
I don't know, Princess Jasmine. Am I?
-哗，朗纳光9伏特手电筒耶
-是啊
-Oh, wow. Lunabeam nine-voIt.
-Yeah.
厉害的玩意儿
WonderfuI piece of hardware, huh?
-对，这是朗纳光9号
-很炫
-That's their titIe, Lunabeam Nine.
-Great.
我喜欢美格光LED手电筒
不过那是我个人喜好
I prefer the MagIite LED myseIf,
but that's just me.
-帮个忙
-什么？
-Do me a huge favor.
-What?
手放口袋里，态度好一点
Shove your hands into your pockets,
put your attitude way down,
对人客气一点
and, aIso, be nice to peopIe.
我能问你一件事吗？
Great. But couId I just ask you
one thing?
-好啊
-我要说清楚
-Yeah.
-Okay, so just to be cIear,
-我不能这么做，对吗？
-好，太夸张了
-so, I can't do this, right?
-Okay, that's actuaIIy crazy.
你打算早死吗？
Did you just make a decision
to possibIy end your Iife
earIier than you were expecting?
我要用手电筒揍你罗
I'm gonna hit you with the fIashIight.
-你在威胁我喔
-不要碰！
-Now you are threatening me. Okay.
-Do not touch it!
-别碰我
-不要碰！
-Don't touch me.
-Do not touch it!
-不要碰！
-别碰我！
-Do not touch it!
-Don't touch me!
我要整天拿手电筒戳你
I'II touch you with my fIashIight
aII day.
手电筒的功能是照明
No, your fIashIight
is meant to iIIuminate.
我要租露营车到处开
I wiII IiteraIIy rent a camper,
拿我的手电筒顶你的胸部
and we wiII drive across America
with my fIashIight on your chest.
-不要这么做
-不要做什么？
-Don't do that.
-Don't do what?
你想看我再做一次吗？
Want to see what happens
when I do it one more time?
-试试看啊
-你乖乖看我这么做吧
-Let's see what happens.
-Watch you do nothing.
你乖乖看我这么做
Let's watch you do nothing
when I do this.
说真的，布兰登，不要…
SeriousIy, Brandon...
-是布朗登
-好，布朗登
-Brundon.
-Brundon,
你搞不清楚我是谁
you do not know who you're deaIing with.
你以为你当警卫很行吗？
You think you know what it means
to be a guard, huh?
相信我，你不懂当警卫的意义
Trust me, you don't know
the meaning of the word.
我碰过你想像不到的事情
I have seen things
that you couId not imagine.
-比如说什么？
-不告诉你
-Like what kind of stuff?
-I'm not gonna teII you.
-你必须放开手电筒
-拜托告诉我
-But you're gonna drop the fIashIight...
-The way you said it,
你本来好像要说很酷的事
it sounded Iike you were gonna say
something cooI.
我不说给你听
Yeah, weII, you don't get to hear it.
放开手电筒
Drop the fIashIight.
我们没事吧？
We cooI?
你刚刚做的事挺酷的
That's actuaIIy pretty cooI,
what you just did.
谢谢
Thank you.
别伤和气吧？
No hard feeIings?
-抱歉，好不好？
-好
-AII right? Sorry.
-Okay.
-我才抱歉
-是我的错，我不该…
-I'm sorry.
-No, It's my fauIt. I shouIdn't have...
两股相对的力量才能引起冲突
No. It takes two opposing forces
to cause friction, and...
你只是尽职责
And you're just doing your job, aII right.
-老兄，保重了
-你也一样
-Take it easy, man.
-Yeah!
那家伙很棒
That guy's great.
更衣室
-我进来了
-好，你在哪里？
-Okay, buddy, I'm in.
-Great. Where are you?
学会的东北角
The northeast corridor of the Castle,
just off the Commons.
史密森尼城堡
-告诉我怎么到档案室
-好
-I need you to taIk me to the Archives.
-Okay.
直走到底右转
At the end of the haII, turn right,
你会在左手边看到楼梯
and there shouId be a stairweII
coming up on your Ieft.
-了解
-下面像迷宫一样
-Got it.
-Now, it's kind of a maze down there.
有通道连接到不同的建筑
Those underground tunneIs
connect a bunch of different buiIdings.
-蛮复杂的
-要快点
-lt could get complicated.
-We'd better hurry,
再28分钟就天黑了
we onIy got 28 minutes tiII sundown.
到B层再左…
When you get down to B level,
you want to take another left...
-尼克？喂？
-爸，听得到吗？
-Nick? HeIIo? Nick?
-Dad! Can you hear...
尼克！
Nick, you're... Nick!
-识别证…布朗登！
-嘿！
-lD, Brundon.
-Hey.
保全
-老兄，再见
-好啊
-Later, dude.
-AII right. Yeah.
好，你们在哪里？
AII right. Where are you guys?
卡士达将军
爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特
飞越大西洋女飞行员第一人
1937失踪于海洋
我的天
Oh, my God.
你这个小捣蛋，我待会再收拾你
You IittIe troubIemaker.
I'm gonna deaI with you Iater.
不！不！不！
No. No! No, no, no!
讲英文通吗？
No, EngIish. EngIish, perhaps.
你是谁？
I'm sorry, who are you?
我是卡曼拉，王中之王
I am Kahmunrah,
the great king of the great kings,
来自古老历史的黑暗深处
and from the darkest depths
of ancient history,
我复活了
I have come back to Iife!
你可能没听到我说的话
Perhaps you did not hear
what I just said.
我是古埃及的法老王
我原本死了
I am a centuries-oId Egyptian Pharaoh.
I was dead,
但是我复活了！
but now I have come back to Iife!
我听到了，我懂，欢迎你回来
Yeah, no. I heard that.
I got that. WeIcome back.
-你是谁？
-达理小发明的赖瑞达理
-Who are you?
-Larry DaIey. DaIey Devices?
在纽约，我认识你弟阿卡曼拉
It's up in New York. It's funny,
I know your brother, Ahkmenrah.
-是吗？
-对
-Do you?
-Yeah.
他认识老么，最受宠的儿子
He knows baby brother.
The favorite son.
-好孩子
-可不是吗？
-Yeah, good kid.
-Isn't he just?
爸妈把最好的都给他
You know, Mother and Father aIways
gave him the best of everything,
全都给他，连王位都给他了
and I do mean everything.
They even gave him the throne.
王位是我的才对
The throne which was rightfuIIy mine!
-他没提
-我打赌他不会提
-He never mentioned that.
-I'II just bet he didn't.
卡曼拉的时代降临了
因为我复…
WeII, now begins the era of Kahmunrah,
because I have come back to...
算了，把刻写板给我
Never mind, just hand me the tabIet.
-巨无霸，不能给他！
-不能给他！
-Don't give it to him, Gigantor!
-Keep him away!
里面的人，给我安静！
SiIence! SiIence in there, pIease!
-别逼我进去
-别想堵我的嘴
-Don't make me come in there!
-No! I won't be muzzIed!
刻写板比你达理小发明的赖瑞达理
Look, that tabIet is more powerfuI
想像的法力强大
than you, Larry DaIey of DaIey Devices,
can possibIy imagine.
复活只是小把戏
Bringing things back to Iife
is just a parIor trick.
有了它，我能打开阴间之门
With it, I shaII unIock
the Gate to the UnderworId
从阴间召唤我的军队
and bring forth my army
from the Land of the Dead.
所以，不麻烦的话
So, if it's not too much troubIe...
请你交出来
...hand it over.
好，拿去
Okay, here you go.
聪明的决定
Wise decision.
抱歉，我以为你想要方块
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry, I thought
you wanted the Cube, but...
方块？
The Cube?
魔术方块
The Cube of Rubik.
好，什么是魔术方块？
AII right, what is
this Cube of Rubik, then?
这个方块能把反对者化为灰烬
The Cube. You know, the one
that turns aII who oppose you to dust?
那个呀
That one? Whatever. I thought...
算了，是我的错
It was my bad, 'cause...
You know what? By the way,
对了，安全起见
your brother didn't want
to mess with it, either.
你弟也不想碰
Yeah, he wanted to pIay it safe, too.
你让我觉得是勇于冒险的人
Just, you sort of struck me
as a next-IeveI sort of guy, so I was...
赖瑞，我可不是我弟
I am not my brother, Larry.
我会马上杀了你跟你的朋友
I wiII kiII you and your friends
in the bIink of an eye.
带我去找魔术方块吧
Now take me to this Cube of Rubik.
-在那里
-打开吧
-Here it is.
-Open it.
回来，把刻写板还我
Come back here!
Come back here with my tabIet!
你的朋友还在我手里！
I stiII have your friends!
-你来骑！
-什么？
-Take the wheeI!
-What?
我叫你骑，开战了，我喜欢
I said, take the wheeI! Oh, we're
in it now! I Iove it! I Iove it!
好好骑，其余的交给我处理
Just keep her straight,
I'II handIe the rest.
冲啊！
Now, charge!
-你的计划是什么？
-美国人不计划的，做就对了
-Okay, so what's the pIan here?
-We're Americans! We don't pIan, we do!
抓稳了！
Now hoId on!
看到了吗？做了再说，每次都管用
See that? Act first, think Iater!
Works every time!
有我罩你！
You're in good hands!
美国第七骑兵队的卡士达将军
GeneraI George A. Custer
of the Fighting U.S. 7th CavaIry,
随时为你服务
at your service.
我很好，开快点啊，笨蛋！
I'm good, I'm good! FIy, you fooI!
英雄，大家在吵什么？
What's the rumpus, ace?
小姐，走开
Look, Iady, couId you
get out of the way?
你叫谁小姐？我叫爱蜜莉亚
Lady? Who are you caIIing Iady?
The name is AmeIia.
爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特
你听过我吗？
AmeIia Earhart!
Perhaps you've heard of me?
对，你是有名的飞行员什么的
Oh, right.
You're a famous piIot or whatever.
飞行员？
我是第一个飞越大西洋的女人
PiIot? I was the first woman
to fIy the AtIantic!
十字飞行勋章第一个女得主
First woman to receive the FIying Cross,
开直升机横越48州第一个女人
first woman to fIy across the 48 states
in a gyroprop.
请你表情放轻松
Now if you'd wipe that perhaps-permanent
Iook of aIarm off your kisser,
跟我说我在哪里
I was wondering if you might be so kind
as to teII me exactIy where I am.
你在博物馆里头，其实是底下
You're in a museum.
Or, actuaIIy, under it.
我目前处境危险
And I'm in kind of a dangerous
situation right now,
你最好不要接近我
so you might not want to be
anywhere near me.
-你的速度好快
-你叫什么名字？
-Wow, you're fast.
-What's your name, fIyboy?
我叫赖瑞达理
My name is Larry DaIey.
赖瑞达理，你没在听吗？
WeII, Larry DaIey,
in case you weren't Iistening,
我不是会闪避危险的人
I'm not one to shy away from danger.
那矛呢？你会闪避矛吗？
How about spears?
Are you one to shy away from spears?
快走吧，我们来找乐子吧
Let's ankIe, skipper!
Now we're gonna have some fun.
98、99，好了
Ninety-eight, ninety-nine, bingo!
就像金羊毛一样
Like a GoIden FIeece.
好了，你们的敌人抓我
AII right, troops,
when your enemies captured me,
他们也成了我的敌人
they made themseIves
my enemies as weII.
大错特错啊
Big mistake. Big mistake.
好，这是我的计划
AII right, here's the pIan.
第三次号角响起时，我会大喊攻击
On the third bugIe bIast,
I shaII IoudIy announce, ''Attack! ''
这时候，我们就从这里冲出去
At which point,
we wiII aII jump out of this box
展开攻击
and attack.
吓死他们，你们觉得怎样？
Mind bomb. What do you think?
你，莎卡佳瓦娜瓦佳达佳达
You, Sacaja...
这不是我的名字
That is not my name.
-莎卡佳米雅
-不对
-Sacajamea.
-No.
-盒子里的小莎
-不是
-Sack-in-a-box.
-No.
-辛可梅雅
-我知道你是有名的将军
-Cinco de Mayo.
-I know you are a famous generaI...
没事，我跟你一样是普通人
That's aII right, that's aII right.
I'm a person, just Iike you.
可是大喊攻击
But won't yeIIing, ''Attack! ''
aIert the enemy
不就是通知敌人我们要攻击吗？
that we are about to attack?
什么？
What?
对，我想是吧
Yeah, I guess so.
达理先生，你挺红的嘛
You're quite the popuIar feIIow,
Mr. DaIey.
你为什么不落跑？
Why don't you just skedaddIe?
我不行，我朋友被关在底下
I can't skedaddIe.
My friends are being heId down there.
我得另外找路下去
I got to go get them.
I got to find another way down.
哇，之前没遇过
This is new.
没事，我不会伤害你们
Hey, it's aII right.
I don't want to hurt you.
达理先生，他们怕的不是你
I don't think it's you
they're afraid of, Mr. DaIey.
跟你交换，谢了
Trade you. Thanks.
退后，给我退后！
Back off! Just back off!
我戳你们喔
I wiII fork you!
你呢？
How about you, huh?
千万别派男孩做女人的事
Never send a boy to do a woman's job.
我在密克罗尼西亚玩过长矛打猎
I spent two weeks spear-hunting
with a tribe in Micronesia.
那里的人反应比较慢
The Micronesians had
much sIower refIexes.
快走！
Come on!
结束了！结束了！
It's over! It's over! It's aII over!
太了不起了
WeII, this is one humdinger
of a hootenanny.
抱歉，对不起
Excuse me. Sorry. Excuse me.
1945年收讯满格耶
Wow, four bars in 1945.
-喂？
-爸，你终于接电话了
-HeIIo?
-Dad, finally!
我研究了档案室的平面图
I've been studying
these pIans to the Archives.
你下楼以后…
Looks Iike once
you get down the stairweII...
我离楼梯可远了
Oh, I'm way past the stairweII, Nicky.
-你找到大家了吗？
-算是
-So you found everyone?
-Sort of.
那是什么玩意？
What is that fIibberty-widget
you are taIking to?
-那是谁？
-爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特
-Who's that?
-It's AmeIia Earhart.
你找到爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特？
You found AmeIia Earhart?
嘿！
I... Hey!
-等一下
-你急什么？
-Wait a minute!
-Buddy, what's your hurry?
-战争结束了
-抱歉，这些人在追我
-Didn't you hear? The war's over!
-Sorry. These guys are chasing me.
这是在办嘉年华吗？
What? What am I Iooking at, Mardi Gras?
-你是哪个单位的？
-我是布鲁克林人
-What unit are you from?
-I'm from BrookIyn.
你说真的？我住中布鲁克林耶
What? Are you serious?
I'm from FIatbush! Hey, feIIas!
各位，这些人想扁我朋友
These so-and-so's are trying
to rough up my paI here
因为他是布鲁克林人
just 'cause he's from BrookIyn!
-谢了
-没问题，打啊！
-Thank you!
-You got it! Fight!
先生，你忘了你的…
Hey, mister! You forgot your...
这是什么鬼东西啊
What the heck is this thing?
抱歉，介意我卡位吗？
Excuse me. Mind if I get in here?
达理先生，就等你了
Any time you're done, Mr. DaIey.
-打电话给我！
-谢啦
-CaII me!
-Thank you for that.
达理先生，你很会施展魅力喔
So you're quite the smooth operator,
aren't you, Mr. DaIey?
快点！
Quick!
-有用耶
-接下来呢？
-That actuaIIy worked.
-What's next?
我没别的意思
Look, nothing personaI, but I'm kind of
in the middIe of something here
不过我的混战不该扯上你
that's not reaIIy your fight.
是因为我是女人吗？
It's because I'm a woman, isn't it?
不是
是因为死而复活的坏法老王想杀我
No, it's because I've got this ancient
raised-from-the-dead eviI Pharaoh guy
好夺走刻写板
who's wiIIing to kiII me and probabIy
anyone near me to get this tabIet
这样他才能统治世界
so he can ruIe the worId.
果然是因为我是女人
So it is because I'm a woman!
-我…
-等等，要不是我
-Look, I...
-No, you Iook, Mr. DaIey!
你还在那团黑白大混乱里面
If it weren't for me, you'd stiII be
Iost in that monochromatic mayhem !
-什么？
-黑白照啦，笨蛋
-Lost in what?
-BIack and white photo, you boob!
听好，我可以帮你
Now Iisten, and Iisten good.
I can heIp you.
我想帮不是因为我喜欢你
我目前并没有
I want to heIp you, and not because
I Iike you, which so far I don't,
而是因为我闻到冒险的味道
我想参一脚
but because I smeII adventure,
and, damn it, I want in.
好，出了事可别怪我
Okay. Don't bIame me
if something happens to you.
我好幸运喔
I shouId be so Iucky.
我是卡曼拉，我是半个神
I am Kahmunrah. I am haIf god,
我妈这边的一等亲
once removed on my mother's side,
埃及的合法统治者
rightfuI ruIer of Egypt,
future ruIer of...
未来要统治一切
WeII, everything eIse.
我损失一些人马
Now, I have Iost some men.
所以我需要新的将军
So, I am in need of some new generaIs
to join me in my IittIe pIan
加入我征服世界的计划
of conquering this worId.
恐怖伊凡
Ivan the TerribIe.
拿破仑波拿巴
NapoIeon Bonaparte.
跟年轻的艾尔卡彭
And young AI Capone.
没错
Yeah.
历史上最卑鄙、最可怕的领导者
Some of the most despicabIe,
most feared Ieaders in aII of history.
各位
GentIemen,
很高兴认识你们
reaIIy, it's just fantastic
to meet you aII.
-我们也是
-我也是
-And us, too.
-And me, you.
你们效忠我，我就会以世界做为回报
AII I ask is your aIIegiance,
and in return, I offer you the worId.
有问题吗？
LiteraIIy. Are there any questions?
我有一个问题，你为什么穿洋装？
Yeah, I got one.
How come you're wearing a dress?
这不是洋装，这是束腰外衣
This is not a dress. This is a tunic.
这是三千年前流行的穿着
It was the height of fashion
3,000 years ago, I assure you.
还有其他问题吗？
Are there any other questions?
我们也要穿
Da. This dress you're wearing,
你穿的这种洋装吗？
do we have to wear one of these, too?
不用，你们没在听吗？
Were you not Iistening?
I just toId Mr. Capone here
我刚跟卡彭说这不是洋装
that this is not a dress.
这是束腰外衣，跟洋装差别很大
It is, in fact, a tunic.
Very big difference.
还有其他问题吗？
Are there any other questions?
跟洋装或束腰外衣
Any questions not about the dress?
无关的问题
Tunic?
那好，月光在消逝
AII right, then. MoonIight is wasting,
-时间很短
-短？
-and the time is short.
-Short?
你干嘛看着我说短？
Why do you Iook at me
when you say ''short''?
抱歉，我是无心的
Sorry. It sIipped out.
如果要称霸世界
Da. If we are taIking
about worId domination,
我当然很有兴趣
then of course, I am interested.
不过我要先澄清一件事
让大家清楚我的为人
But first I want to cIarify something
so you know what you are getting.
大家老是说恐怖伊凡很恐怖
PeopIe aIways say,
''Ivan the TerribIe, he's so terribIe.
我好怕伊凡，碰到他就惨了
''I'm so scared of Ivan. He's bad news.''
事实上，正确的翻译是
When in fact,
the correct transIation is
神奇伊凡
''Ivan the Awesome''.
神奇伊凡？
Ivan the Awesome?
这样不太顺口吧
It's not reaIIy as catchy, is it?
恐怖伊凡真的很响亮
I mean, ''Ivan the TerribIe'',
that reaIIy pops.
可是我不恐怖，我是有效率的领导者
But I wasn't terribIe. In fact,
I was quite an effective Ieader.
了解
DuIy noted. Now, I'd Iike to wrap up
the oId meet-and-greet
这场会面就以一个问题结束吧
by asking you gentIemen a question.
你们要加入我吗？
Are you with me?
-好啊
-好
-Yeah. Yeah, sure.
-Oui.
-可是…
-那就把达理小发明的赖瑞达理
-Da, but...
-Then bring Larry DaIey of DaIey Devices
跟阿卡曼拉的刻写板带来给我！
and the GoIden TabIet of Ahkmenrah
to me!
我会带你回去找你朋友
We'II get you back down
to your chums, Mr. DaIey.
跟着爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特不会走丢
You won't get Iost
foIIowing AmeIia Earhart.
快躲起来
Quick, get down.
达理先生，我喜欢你搂我的方式
WeII, weII, Mr. DaIey,
I quite Iike the way you're hoIding me.
抱歉，我不是要…
No. Sorry, I wasn't trying to...
达理先生，别再鬼扯了
Oh, pIease,
stop beating your gums, Mr. DaIey.
我们认识后
You haven't been abIe
to take your cheaters off my chassis
你就一直瞄我
since the moment we met.
我真的不知道你在说什么
I IiteraIIy didn't understand
one word of that.
我幻听吗？还是有音乐？
Is it just me
or is there music in the air?
我们能永远放光芒
...my baby, we can make it shine
We can take forever...
小天使，安静
You! LittIe fIying angeI things! Quiet!
他们是爱神丘比特
They're cupids, Mr. DaIey. Gods of Iove.
爱神，闭嘴，我们想躲起来
Great. Gods of Iove, wouId you shut up?
PIease shut up. We're trying to hide.
耶，十足女人，耶
Yeah! More than a woman! Yeah!
不用换风格
唱原来那首歌，安静
No, don't change the arrangement,
it's not about the arrangement. Quiet!
耶，超酷、超
Kick the chorus, y'aII!
十足女人
More than a woman
夜班警卫，秀出你的本事吧
Yo, show me what you got,
night guard!
快走
AII right, come on. Let's go.
对我来说是十足女人
More than a woman to me
十足女人
More than a woman
她是十足女人
She's more than a woman
小矮个，小老鼠扑向
And so, the IittIe tiny man who
couId not be a smaIIer or shorter mouse
大猫的爪子了
runs into the cIaws of the giant cat!
你真的超在意高度的
You're reaIIy hung up
on the height, aren't you?
-这跟高度没有关系
-你很在意
-No, it's not about height, see...
-Yes, you are.
你说我是老鼠，你是大猫
You're saying I'm a IittIe mouse,
you're a giant cat.
-我是大猫呀
-我没别的意思
-I am the giant cat.
-No offense, I just...
你是拿破仑，你有矮子情结
You're NapoIeon.
There's a compIex named after you.
你矮得出名
You're famous for being IittIe,
and it's true. Look.
你这个天真的美国小子
Oh, you naive American man-boy.
我们没要开打，所以不该…
Look. Neither of us are gonna
be jamming anytime soon, right?
这根本没啥好争的
So it's not Iike we shouId...
It's not even an issue.
这跟高度没关系，而是精明的计划
It's not about height or something eIse.
It's a pIan. It's a briIIiant pIan.
-计划喔
-皇帝，聪明的计划
-So it was a pIan.
-Snazzy maneuver, Emperor.
小姐，谢谢
Merci, mademoiselle.
麻烦你男友跟我走吧
Now, if your boyfriend
wouId kindIy come with me...
我不是她的男友
I'm not her boyfriend.
-不是她的男友
-不是
-Not her boyfriend.
-No.
只是朋友吗？
Just friends?
-对，朋友
-认识，朋友
-Yeah, friends.
-Acquaintances. Friends.
你们是大学朋友
Were you guys, Iike, friends in coIIege
害怕告诉对方
and just afraid now
to both ruin your reIationship
你想要不只是朋友
by teIIing the other person
that you want to be more than friends,
会打坏关系吗？
that you Iike-Iike each other?
再说一次，好吗？
抱歉，我没听懂
One more time?
I'm sorry. I didn't catch the...
你们是大学朋友
Were you guys, Iike, friends in coIIege
害怕告诉对方
and now both afraid
to ruin your reIationship
你想要的不只是朋友
by teIIing the other person
that you want to be more than friends,
会打坏关系吗？
that you Iike-Iike each other?
-没有
-没有吗？
-No.
-No?
我最爱把关系搞清楚，法国人都这样
I just Iove the nitty-gritty of
reIationships. AII us French do.
-对
-爱情
-Great.
-Yes. Amour!
-现在…
-是
-Now.
-Yeah?
-…你不跟我走就受死
-好
-This way, or you die.
-Yes.
-我跟你们去
-我们的战争跟你无关
-Wait, I'm coming with you!
-No! Our fight is not with you.
-再下注
-好
-...so you gotta bet a second time.
-AII right. Okay.
我的头发在欧洲可是能卖钱的
My hair is currency
in certain parts of Europe.
没错，就像黄金跟纸钞有价值
It's true.
Currency, Iike goId or paper money.
有教堂拿一撮就卖了
The Duomo was purchased
with just one Iocket.
听着，他很瞎
Listen up, kemosabe.
松饼跟苍蝇拍傻傻分不清楚
This rodeo cIown wouIdn't know
a fIapjack from a fIyswatter.
巨无霸在外面为我们拼命
Now, Gigantor's out there
risking his hide for us.
我们得帮他
The Ieast we can do
is give him some heIp.
我们困在里头可帮不了忙，是吧
Some big heIp. But we can't very weII do
that if we're stuck in here, now, can we?
我们得逃出去
We need to escape.
松饼是什么？
What's a fIapjack?
就像饼干或司康饼
It's Iike a biscuit or a scone.
-击胸吧
-耶
-Chest bump?
-Yeah.
你看
Then deadIy. Watch.
牌看好，现在下注
Guard your cards, okay? Now you bet.
好，出牌
Okay, now you got
to throw some cards down.
-准备好了吗？
-好了
-Ready?
-Ready.
一点都不好玩
Say something. Say anything.
This is no fun. You're supposed to...
-你们在干嘛？
-屋大维，快跑
-Hey! What are you two doing out here?
-Octavius, go!
-快跑啊，我来拖住他们
-我不会抛下你的
-You, make a run for it, I'II hoId them off!
-I wiII not Ieave you!
没空管道义了，快走吧
Ain't no time for your Roman meIodrama !
Now, get! Go!
我不会有事的
OId Jedediah wiII be fine.
你现在自身难保了
Now, you're in reaI troubIe.
这不是真的红宝石
Why, these aren't reaI rubies at aII.
什么红宝石鞋嘛
Ruby sIippers indeed.
不过不管你是谁，你的宝座还真舒服
But, whoever you are, Archie Bunker,
you had one comfortabIe throne.
老大
Hey, boss.
我抓到这个想从一个洞落跑的
Caught this one trying to escape
through a rust hoIe in the crate.
他的小朋友溜了
One of his IittIe friends got away.
拜托，他们哪有杀伤力
Oh, pIease.
What damage couId they possibIy do?
他们跟米粒一样大，不是吗？
Why, they're no bigger than
a IittIe grain of couscous. Aren't you?
我听你说话想到两个词
You know, two words come to mind
when I hear you taIk.
神经病跟怪喀
''DeIusionaI'' and ''weirdo''.
要说第三个的话是瞎，很瞎
And if I had to say a third, ''goofy''.
Just goofy.
你不放我走，我就要发火罗
Now you Iet oId Jedediah out of here
or he's gonna get angry.
嘉地雅，说得好
WeII pIayed, Jedediah!
抱歉，我没办法把你当一回事
I'm sorry, I can't take you seriousIy.
You're just adorabIe,
你连恐吓我都很可爱
even when you're threatening me.
It's hiIarious.
是我个人喜好吗？
还是这些家伙可爱到不行？
Is it just me,
or are these guys unbeIievabIy cute?
等一下
Now hoId it a second, now.
你抓我刑求我都行
Now, you have a right to keep me
as your captive, torture me, even,
千万别说我可爱
but don't caII me cute! I ain't cute!
冷静啊，朋友
活下去，我会来找你的
Steady, my friend!
Just stay aIive! I wiII find you!
巨无霸，不
Gigantor. No!
达理先生，很高兴又见面了
HeIIo, Mr. DaIey. Nice to see you again.
不介意的话，我要拿走刻写板
Now, if you don't mind,
I shaII take that from you.
谢谢
Thank you.
过了三千年，终于到手了
FinaIIy. FinaIIy! After 3,000 years,
我的地狱邪恶大军，我美丽的军队
my eviI army of the damned,
my beautifuI, beautifuI army,
终于要倾巢而出了
shaII be unIeashed!
爸妈恐怕把密码
I'm afraid that Mother
and Father may have
偷偷改掉了
sIightIy changed the combination on me.
你们没要接管底下世界了
I guess this whoIe
unIeashing-the-underworId thing
你一定很闷，是吧？
isn't reaIIy working out for you, huh?
因为你等了
It must be reaIIy frustrating,
'cause you've waited thousands of years
几千年才复活
to come back from the dead
and everything,
结果你现在却打不开
and now you can't get it open.
别怕，必要的话我会再等一千年
Fear not, for I shaII wait
a thousand more if I must.
很好，因为再过几小时
你就会在很闷的姿势僵住
Good, 'cause in a few hours you'II be
standing here in a frustrated position,
我会跟我朋友闪人，事情就落幕了
frozen, and I'II waIk out of here
with my buddies and that'II be that.
所以，我有整晚的时间
So, I got aII night.
整晚是吗？
ReaIIy? AII night? WeII!
他就没有了
He doesn't.
把笼子打开
Open that cage.
-你在干嘛？
-不要碰我！
-What are you doing?
-No touching! No touching!
别弄我啊
Don't you manhandIe me!
-你看，他在发小脾气
-阿嘉？
-Look, he's having a IittIe tantrum.
-Jed?
别乱扭，这样对你只会更糟
Don't you squirm ! Don't squirm.
It'II onIy be worse for you.
-把他放下来！
-别怕
-Put him down!
-Don't be afraid.
我不会伤害你
I shan't hurt you.
糟糕，我瞎掰的
I Iied.
达理先生，他可没整晚的时间
I don't think he has aII night
at aII, Mr. DaIey.
看样子，我认为他有一个多小时
From the Iooks of things,
I'd say he has a IittIe over an hour.
放我出去！
Take me out of here!
你是警卫，你清楚刻写板
You were the guardian!
You know aII about this tabIet.
你显然比大家都聪明
You're obviousIy much more cIever
than the rest of us.
不管你知不知道密码
You may or may not
know the combination,
我给你一小时搞定
but I am going to give you
exactIy one hour to figure it out.
不然，我就杀了你的朋友
If you do not,
I shaII kiII your friends.
你别想逃，我会看着你
And pIease don't think about escaping,
for I shaII be watching you.
我根本不会
Look, I don't even know how to begin
破解这东西
to decipher this thing,
aII right? ReaIIy.
可惜啊，你的小牛仔朋友
What a pity.
看起来是大好人一个
And your IittIe cowboy friend seemed
Iike such a charming IittIe feIIow.
达理先生，时间紧迫
计时开始了
Ah, weII. Tick-tock, Mr. DaIey.
Your hour has begun.
伙计，你行的，我知道你行
Hey! You got this, partner.
I know you do.
你行的！
You got this!
你在这里，你还好吗？
我担心死了
There you are! Are you aII right?
I've been worried sick! Sick I teII you.
-我没事
-我们的下一步是什么？
-No, I'm fine.
-So what's our next move, partner?
我不知道，我得解读刻写板
I don't know. I just got to get
this tabIet transIated.
太好了，又是这家伙
Oh, great! This guy again.
听着，我们不想惹事，好吗？
Look, buddy,
we don't want any troubIe, aII right?
你看
Look at that!
大胆的章鱼不喜欢离开水
I guess our sassy cephaIopod was just a
fish who didn't Iike being out of water.
它其实没那么坏
He's not such a baIIywagger after aII.
好，你开心我就高兴了
Okay. GIad you're happy.
哈罗，帮个忙好吗？
HeIIo? A IittIe assistance?
-是泰迪，太好了！
-是！
-Hey, Teddy! Perfect!
-Yes!
说不定你能帮我们
Maybe you couId heIp us.
重要的事先解决
I'd Iove to heIp you,
but first things first.
我鼻子痒到快发疯了
My nose is so itchy,
it's driving me insane.
我不想麻烦你
不过我的身体少了几截
I hate to ask, but, as you see,
I'm missing a few body parts.
-你能帮忙抓一下吗？
-好啊
-CouId you pIease give us a scratch?
-Yeah, sure.
太好了，好爽，过去一点
Oh, yes! That's exquisite.
A IittIe over there...
-还要吗？
-继续
-Yes!
-More?
喔，太棒了
Oh, yes! Yes! Oh, that's...
好爽
Sweet rutabaga pie, that was divine.
希欧多罗斯福在此为你服务
Theodore RooseveIt, at your service.
第26任美国总统、游骑兵
Twenty-sixth President
of the United States, Rough Rider,
国家公园的创办人什么的
founder of the nationaI parks,
and a whoIe bunch of other stuff.
-我们见过吗？
-没有，有另一个泰迪
-Have we met?
-No, there's another Teddy.
-纽约有个你
-真的？另一个我是什么样子？
-We have one of you in New York.
-ReaIIy? What's he Iike, this other me?
差不多，除了…
He's pretty much the same,
except with...
除了什么？有身体吗？
Except what? Say it.
Except with a body?
-对，他有身体
-可恶，太痛苦了！
-Yes. He has a body.
-Oh, dash it, the pain!
-他还有一匹马…
-麻烦一下
-And a horse.
-Excuse me!
我们需要人翻译上面的文字
We reaIIy need someone to transIate
what's written on this tabIet.
-你看得懂象形文字吗？
-小姐，我懂
-Do you read hierogIyphics?
-Yes, I do, missy.
这很简单
That's a simpIe one.
鸟、持矛的人、横的鱼
甲虫、瓶子
Bird. Man with spear.
Sideways fish. BeetIe. Vase.
这是什么意思？
Okay, and what does that mean?
意思是…这只是大概的翻译
It means, and this is
just a rough transIation,
一个持矛的人抓了一只鸟跟横鱼
放进瓶子里
''A man with a spear trapped a bird
and a sideways fish in a vase.
“还有一只甲虫”
''And there was aIso a beetIe.''
-我觉得不是这样
-这是一个可能的翻译
-I don't think that's it.
-That's just one possibIe transIation.
另一个是
Another possibIe transIation is,
想找到密码
''You wiII find the combination you seek
“就要先解开法老王陵寝中心之谜”
''if you figure out the secret
at the heart of Pharaoh's tomb.''
-这是什么意思？
-我是出谜题的吗？
-Okay, and what does that mean?
-I don't know! What am I, the Sphinx?
你怎么不问纽约的泰迪
''What's this? What's that?''
Why don't you ask New York Teddy?
他一定会很想动手碰
I'm sure he'd Iove to get his grabby
IittIe fingers aII over that thing!
搞不好还让他的马舔一舔
ProbabIy Iet his horse Iick it, too!
我们应该去雕像馆了
Mr. DaIey, we shouId be going
to the scuIpture gaIIery.
那里有个人可能会有更好的想法
I think there's someone there
who might have a better thought on this.
我们要找的人就在底下
The feIIow we're Iooking for
is just down here.
-晚安
-哈罗，小姐
-Bonsoir.
-HeIIo, young Iady.
抱歉，我们可以走了吗？
Hey, excuse me.
CouId we keep moving, pIease?
可以啊，可是这样会错过难得的机会
We certainIy couId, but then
we might miss a rare opportunity.
达理先生，她可是窦加的作品
I mean, she is a Degas, Mr. DaIey.
可是我有个朋友困在沙漏里
Okay, it's just I got a IittIe buddy
stuck in an hourgIass,
早上还要开会，快走了
I got a pitch meeting
at WaI-Mart in the morning...
-我们走吧…
-他就在这里
-It wouId be great if we couId...
-He's right here.
我觉得他对这件事会有想法
I think he'II have a thought on this.
沉思者铜像-1902年作品
罗丹-生于1840逝于1917
Mr. Thinker, we're sorry
to interrupt your contempIation,
沉思者，抱歉打扰你沉思了
我们得解开
but we reaIIy need
to figure out the secret
法老王陵寝中心之谜
at the heart of Pharaoh's tomb.
沉思啊，我在沉思
I'm thinking. I'm thinking.
我在想
I'm thinking.
-想啊想
-不行，他是逊咖
-I'm thinking.
-It's not happening with him.
喔，哇
Oh, wow.
不会吧，你看，有漂亮美眉耶
You've gotta be kidding me.
Check that out!
-喔，耶
-嘿，嘿！
-Oh, yeah.
-Hey! Hey!
老兄，看这里，事情很严重
Buddy! Over here! This is serious.
关系到生死
ApparentIy, it's a matter
of Iife and death.
我告诉你什么关系到生死
I'II teII you
what's a matter of Iife and death.
那位辣妹
That beautifuI Iady over there.
宝贝，看我的肌肉
Hey, baby! Check out the gun show
going on over here!
火力十足
Firepower!
他不是爱因斯坦
He's certainIy no Einstein.
-二头肌！三角肌…
-你说得对
-Biceps! DeItoids...
-Yeah.
-等等，我有看到一堆
-一堆什么？
-Wait a minute. I saw a bunch of those.
-A bunch of whats?
-小爱因斯坦
-在哪里？
-LittIe Einsteins.
-Where?
在那边，航太馆
Over there, in Air and Space.
我们得过去
I gotta get over there.
干嘛？
What?
-没事
-好，那你瞪着我干嘛？
-Nothing.
-Okay. Then why are you staring at me?
我不想错过这一刻
I don't wanna miss a moment.
我们得走了，因为…
AII right, good, but we shouId
get going, 'cause we...
-干嘛
-你话太多了
-Why?
-You taIk too much, ace.
我不知道我为什么亲你
I don't know why I did that, Mr. DaIey.
我觉得我睡了好久
I just feeI as if I've been asIeep
for a Iong time and now, suddenIy,
突然醒了过来
I'm awake.
这点我可以解释
I can expIain that...
我真的可以
But reaIIy, I couId. I reaIIy...
又来了，为什么？
Again, why?
太好了，你们回来了
Great, you're back.
好，很好
Okay. Yeah. Great.
太好了，是《铁达尼号》主题曲
好听，可是不适合
Love theme from Titanic.
Good, but not reaIIy appropriate.
你不喜欢享乐，对吗？
You don't Iet yourseIf enjoy things
much, do you, Mr. DaIey?
不是歌选得不好
Okay, you know what?
It's not reaIIy the song choice.
而是你们唱得不太准
And by the way, you're a IittIe pitchy.
我觉得你们很棒，造型抢眼
WeII, I thought you were amazing,
and you Iook wonderfuI.
拜托你们飞走好吗？
CouId you just fIy away, pIease?
继续冒险吧
And so the adventure continues.
我是怎么说的，够了！
What did I teII you? Enough!
我是拳王阿里
我的确觉得像只飘逸的蝴蝶
You know, I do sort of feeI
Iike a fIoating butterfIy.
你完全疯了
You are crazier than a road Iizard.
埃及先生
这两个听说我们要接管世界
Mr. Egypt, these two here heard
that we're taking over the worId
他们想参一脚，我不知道他们是谁
and they want in.
I don't know who they are,
不过他们也是这里的展品
but they're on exhibit here,
too, apparentIy.
我根本搞不清楚他们是什么
I don't even know what they are.
抱歉，今天恶魔的名额满了
I'm sorry, but we're aII fuII up
in our axis of eviI today. Sorry.
别这样，我很坏耶
Come on! But I'm bad! I'm bad!
我能使坏给你看
Hey, I couId show you how bad I am !
怕我吧！
Fear me!
抱歉，我不信
I'm sorry. I'm just not buying it.
你看起来不是坏
你只是看起来不太爽
You don't seem very bad. You just seem
sort of vagueIy grouchy to me.
真是的
Oh, boy.
你在干嘛？这是什么？
What are you doing?
What is that? What is this?
这是啥意思？我被你搞糊涂了
What does it mean? You've Iost me.
这是你的呼吸声吗？
吵得我不能想事情
Is that you breathing?
Because I can't hear myseIf think.
我可以给个建议吗？
Can I make one suggestion
to you, my friend? Just simpIify.
简单一点，你搞得太复杂了
There's just too much going on here.
你邪恶、有气喘、还是机器人
这斗蓬是干嘛的？
You're eviI, you're asthmatic, you're
a robot... And what is the cape for?
我们要去听歌剧吗？没有吧
Are we going to the opera?
I don't think so.
抱歉，再见
Sorry! Goodbye.
注意了！
Attention!
他拿着刻写板走了
He's Ieaving with the tabIet!
哪里？
Where?
给我
Give me that.
他没要解开密码，他是要落跑
He's not trying to figure out the...
He's trying to escape!
大家快去，杀了他
把刻写板拿回来
Go. Go! AII of you! KiII him !
And bring me that tabIet.
快点啊
没有刻写板，我们就没局了
Come on, peopIe! Let's go!
Without that tabIet, we've nothing!
步兵，快去！
Streltsy! Go!
赖瑞达理，你以为你逃得掉吗？
Thought you couId get away,
didn't you, Larry DaIey?
我们没救了乎
Criminy, we're jimmy-jacked.
-没救了乎？
-这是我说话的方式
-Jimmy-jacked? ReaIIy?
-It's the way I speak.
就连你说听起来都像瞎掰的
Yeah, I know, but that one
sounds made up, even for you.
“不会吧，坏人挡了我们的路”
这样说不好玩
''Oh, no, our path has been bIocked
by bad peopIe.'' What's the fun in that?
重点是我们进不了航太馆
The point is, we're not getting into
the Air and Space right now.
-你说得对
-我们没救了乎
-You're right. We are jimmy-jacked.
-Jimmy-jacked.
走吧
Come on.
听说这里的总统是好人
They say a good man ruIes this union.
我答应嘉地雅我会搬救兵
I promised Jedediah I wouId bring heIp,
我一定会搬来
and heIp I wiII bring.
冲啊！
Charge!
我算错距离了
Misjudged the distance.
谁在那里？
Who's there?
朱比特，保护我啊
Jupiter, protect me.
千万不要动
Remain very stiII.
它们能察觉动作
They can sense movement.
它们也能听到我自言自语
ApparentIy, they can aIso hear me
taIking to myseIf.
我不是松果
I'm not a nut.
不！
No!
我们能在里头躲一会
We shouId be okay in here for a whiIe.
你当博物馆警卫多久了？
So, how Iong
have you guarded antiquities?
什么？我不是警卫…
What? Oh, no,
I don't actuaIIy work at the...
你的制服很帅
I just thought
with the fancy getup and aII...
这是我借来的
No, I borrowed this.
我在纽约是当过警卫
可是那有一段时间了
I mean, I was a guard back in New York,
but that was a whiIe ago.
你为什么辞职？你做得不开心吗？
So why did you Ieave?
Did you not enjoy it?
我很喜欢
No, I Ioved it. I just...
只是情况变了
Things sort of took off
in a different direction, so...
-你现在做什么？
-我…
-So what do you do now?
-WeII, I sort of...
设计b品来卖
WeII, I sort of design products
and seII them.
-你是发明家
-对
-You're an inventor!
-I am.
我是发明家，我发明东西
I am an inventor, yeah. I invent stuff.
例如火箭吗？
Like the rocket ship?
-不是
-水上飞机
-No.
-The sea pIane.
-飞船？
-不是飞行器
-The dirigibIe?
-No, not aircraft.
是比较小的东西，例如…
Sort of Iike more
smaII-scaIe stuff, Iike...
发光手电筒，那是我的发明
WeII, the GIow-in-the-Dark
FIashIight, that was mine.
你喜欢你的新工作吗？
So this new job, do you Iike it?
我很喜欢，很刺激
Yeah, I Iike it a Iot.
It's exciting. It's...
-干嘛
-我搞不懂
-What?
-I'm just confused, is aII.
如果你觉得不刺激干嘛做
If you're not excited by it,
why do you do it?
-我觉得很刺激啊，我刚说…
-我知道你说什么
-I am excited by it. I just said...
-I know what you said, Mr. DaIey,
可是你看起来没啥活力
but what I see in front of me
is a man who's Iost his moxie.
我没有…
I have not Iost my...
我有活力啊
I got my moxie.
你知道我为什么去当飞行员吗？
Do you know why I became a piIot?
-我不知道
-因为好玩
-I don't, no.
-For the fun of it.
不然做那些事情干嘛？
Why eIse wouId anyone do anything?
不会吧
Great Gatsby!
该死的鸽子，吵个不停
BIast these pigeons
and their incessant cooing!
-总统先生，不要！
-该来巡视…
-No! Mr. President! Sir!
-AII right. Time to see the state...
-请您不要起来！
-…这个伟大的国家了
-PIease don't get up!
-...of this great union! I aIways say,
我一向说，今日事今日毕啊
Ieave nothing for tomorrow
which can be done today.
先生，你出去会吓死人
Sir, if you go out there,
you're gonna freak a Iot of peopIe out!
吓人？我又不是怪物
Freak? I assure you, sir,
I am no freak.
-我不是说你是怪物
-小家伙，过来
-No, I didn't mean you're a freak...
-Come here, IittIe one.
怪物应该是你吧
In fact, if anyone is freakish,
I'm afraid it's you, sir.
其实，你小只到不行
The truth is, you are very smaII.
连对中等体型的人来说都是
And I mean
even for a reguIar-sized human.
什么？你为什么这么说？
What? Why wouId you even say that?
我不能说谎
I must be honest.
对，你是诚实的林肯
抱歉，太好了
Right. Okay, Honest Abe.
Of course. I'm sorry. Great.
总统先生，把这小男人放下来
Come, now, Mr. President,
put the IittIe man down
坐回你的宝座吧
and Iet's sit our fanny back
in that throne of yours.
你的态度很积极，我就照办吧
You have a can-do attitude,
and I shaII do as you ask.
谢谢
Thank you.
-好，放回去
-谢谢
-There you go.
-Thank you.
美国就是有这种积极的精神
It's that very can-do spirit that has
defined this remarkabIe nation of ours.
-告诉你…
-他们来了
-Interesting story.
-They're coming.
有一晚在盖茨堡…
One night in Gettysburg...
总统先生，请你别动
Mr. President, we're gonna need you
to hoId stiII now.
-什么？
-林肯，定格！
-What?
-Abraham, freeze!
定格？我…
Freeze? I...
-谢谢
-不客气
-Thank you.
-You're weIcome.
-我们去航太馆吧
-我觉得你们两个
-Come on, Iet's get to Air and Space.
-If I may,
-很登对
-不，我们不是
-you two make an adorabIe coupIe.
-Oh, no, we're not...
我们不是，我是说…
No, we're not a...
I mean, we're not a...
“我们不是，我是说…”
吵死了！
''We're not a... I mean, we're not a...''
我从来不说谎的！
I never Iie!
事实是，你们两个很登对
The truth is,
you two are adorabIe together.
谢谢，晚安
Thank you. Good night.
再见，漂亮的小姐跟小只男人
FareweII, IoveIy Iady
and smaII, IittIe man.
航太博物馆
去找爱因斯坦吧
Now Iet's see if we can find
these Einsteins of yours.
人类的一大步
One giant leap for a mannequin...
华府，这里是航太馆
我们恢复通讯与运作了
D.C., this is Air and Space. We are
back online and fully operational.
黑色部队又出动了
The Tuskegee Airmen
are on the march once again.
别再说我们的事迹了，活在当下吧
Can you stop narrating everything
we're doing? Just Iive in the moment.
黑色部队活在当下
The Tuskegee Airmen
are Iiving in the moment!
-埃尔哈特小姐？
-是
-Miss Earhart?
-Yes.
-我想谢谢你
-为什么？
-I wanna say thank you.
-What for, Captain?
很多人也认为我们不懂飞行
A Iot of peopIe didn't think
we couId fIy, either.
多谢你开路
Thanks for cIearing the runway, ma'am.
-看谁先到巴黎？
-拼了
-Race you to Paris?
-You're on!
不，先不要！
No! Not now! We gotta...
-过个大西洋就到了
-要赶快找到爱因斯坦
-It's just a quick jaunt over the pond.
-No. Gotta find the Einsteins.
我们没时间，走吧
Come on, we gotta go.
We don't have time. Come on!
抱歉，本性难移
Sorry, it's in the bIood.
达理先生，它在那里
There she is, Mr. DaIey.
这架飞机带我横越大西洋
OId Bessie, the oId famiIy bus.
That gaI took me across the AtIantic!
我想爱因斯坦在这里
Okay. I think the Einsteins
are over here, though.
这是任务控制中心，飞行检查完成
This is Mission Control.
Flight check complete.
-他们去哪里了？
-准备动
-Where'd you go? Where'd they go?
-You are clear for launch.
动！
Contact!
华府，这是任务中心
D.C., this is Mission Control.
-不！不！
-一切就绪，准备发射
-No, no! No!
-All systems go and green for lift-off.
收到，准备发射
Roger that.
We are green for lift-off.
不，我们没要发射任何东西！
No, we're definiteIy not green
for any kind of Iift-off!
-我要知道能不能发射
-不发射，不能发射
-I want a ''go, no-go'' for Iaunch.
-I say no-go. Let's not go.
发射！
Go!
-发射！
-不！不能发射
-Go!
-No! No go!
旋转角度
Torquing angles incoming.
不要旋转
Tone it down with the torque.
Torque it down.
慢下来
De-torque. De-torque.
展开动程序
Commence ignition sequence.
-收到
-执行发射
-Roger that, fIight.
-We have Iaunch commit.
-不，不
-10…
-No. No, no, no!
-Ten,
9、8、7…
nine, eight, seven...
-喂，那是我的
-不要执行
-Hey, that's mine.
-No, we do not have commit.
我们不要进行发射
Repeat. We are decommissioning
the committal of the launch
现在进入不飞不发射阶段
and it is now a negatory launch phase.
We are in a no-fly, no-go phase.
这是飞也不飞阶段
That is a November-Gorgon phase
of non-flying!
-好啦！
-晚安
-Fine!
-And we're gonna say good night.
大家表现很好，完毕
Thank you. Good work. Over and out.
-抱歉
-可恶，真让人失望
-Sorry.
-Damn, that was disappointing.
走吧，我请你喝咖啡
Come on. I'II buy you
a cup of coffee.
嘿，小太空猴子
Hey, IittIe space monkey.
阿布
AbIe.
你是阿布，你好吗？
You're AbIe. Okay, good. How you doing?
很好，稍息
Yes, good. At ease. AII right.
你是有礼貌的小家伙
You're a poIite IittIe feIIa,
aren't you?
你知道爱因斯坦摇头公仔在哪吗？
Hey, you happen to know where those
IittIe Einstein bobbIehead guys are?
达理先生，我找到爱因斯坦了
Mr. DaIey! I found your Einsteins.
太好了
Great. Hey...
各位，我们得破解刻写板的密码
GentIemen, we're trying to crack
the combination of this tabIet doodad,
上面说我们想知道
and the writing here says we'II find it
就得解开法老王陵寝中心之谜
if we figure out the secret
at the heart of Pharaoh's tomb.
很简单，答案就在问题里
That's an easy one.
The answer's in the question.
-什么意思？
-想想看
-What does that mean?
-''Figure out''.
是一个号码
It's a figure! I.e., a number.
法老王陵寝是金字塔
And the Pharaoh's tomb,
i.e. the pyramids.
还不懂吗？你们要找金字塔中心
Don't you get it, kid?
You're Iooking for the secret number
的秘密号码
at the heart of the pyramids.
有了，这个号码是圆周率
WeII, whistIe me Dixie, the answer's pi!
-圆周率？
-准确地说是3.14159265
-Pi?
-3.14159265, to be exact.
3.1495265吗？
Yes! 3.1495265.
不是，3.14159265
No, no, no, 3.14159265.
好，3.14…
Yeah, okay, 3.14...
我看不懂，这是对还不对？
I'm sorry, I can't teII.
Is it yes or no? Cause you just...
我知道这很难，麻烦一下好吗？
I know it's hard, couId you just...
不要碰我的头发
Don't touch the hair.
-对不起，我看不出这是点头还…
-我是摇头公仔耶，笨蛋
-Sorry, I can't teII if it's up or...
-I'm a bobbIehead, dummkopf,
我们就喜欢这样，大家一起来！
and that's the way we Iike it.
AII together, now!
我们就喜欢这样
That's the way
We like it
不是大家都是爱因斯坦嘛
You know,
we can't aII be Einsteins, so...
-我是
-我们是啊
-I can!
-We are!
-你是
-我也是
-He is!
-Me, too!
-好吧
-好，再说一次
-Okay, aII right.
-Okay, here it is.
-好，你们可以说慢一点吗？
-好啦
-Can you sIow it down a IittIe bit?
-Okay.
3.14159265
3.14159265.
-好，3.14…
-我记下了
-Okay. 3.14...
-I've got it.
-爱因斯坦，谢谢
-谢谢了
-Thank you, Mr. Einsteins.
-Thank you.
好，我这个聪明有名的将军
AII right. Now, Iike the briIIiant
and famous generaI that I am,
苦思了你说的话
I thought Iong and hard
about what you said,
我想出改良的新战略了
and I've come up with a brand-new
and improved battIe pIan!
好
Okay.
我要大喊我们不攻击
I wiII IoudIy announce that we are not
然后…
going to attack, and then...
等着喔
Wait for it.
“神奇的卡士达要说啥？
真希望他是我的朋友…”
''What's the amazing Custer about to say
now? I hope he's my friend, or...''
我们就进攻！
We attack!
想不到你的朋友会落跑吧？
Didn't expect your friend
to run off Iike that, did you?
他会回来啦
He's coming back, Ka-Ka-Ro.
他铁定会来的啦
Sure as moon shines on a mongoose,
he'II be here.
如果我是你，就会省口气
I wouId save my breath if I were you.
你的气数不多了
You don't have many Ieft.
我们有10分钟可以救阿嘉
We've got about 10 minutes
to get over there to Jed.
我们是好团队，不只是团队吧
I think we make a good team,
perhaps more than a team.
等等
Wait. Okay, wait.
你不喜欢亲我吗？
What's the matter?
You didn't Iike kissing me?
没有，那很棒，巴掌是有点痛啦
No, I did. It was great. I mean,
the sIapping hurt a IittIe bit, but...
-所以你不喜欢我
-我当然喜欢你，你棒透了
-So you don't Iike me, then.
-Of course I Iike you. You're incredibIe.
你是很棒的人
I think you're an amazing person.
You're...
只是有一些状况让我们不能…
It's just there are certain issues
that wouId prevent us from...
-因为你不是…
-达理先生，我不是什么？
-I just... You're not...
-I'm not what, Mr. DaIey?
好，你是那个做的…
Okay. You're made of...
什么做的？
Made of...
很棒的东西，你很棒
WonderfuI things.
You're made of good, wonderfuI things.
快点，步兵，快上
Come on.
各位，拜托你们拖延他们
GentIemen, couId you
buy us some time pIease?
非得成功不可
It'II have to do.
这是举世第一架飞机耶
No! That's the first pIane ever made!
这是轻木跟纸做的
It's made out of baIsa wood and paper.
这是云杉、帆布做的
还有旧式的美国设计
It's made out of spruce and canvas and
good oId-fashioned American ingenuity.
你来不来？
Are you coming, or what?
-让开！
-办不到
-Out of our way!
-I don't think so.
他们跑了！
They're getting away!
达理先生，抓稳，好玩的来了
Hang on, Mr. DaIey.
Things are about to get interesting.
女飞行员！太夸张了！
A Iady piIot! Preposterous!
-小子，再考虑一下
-她很行
-Think again, boys!
-Oh, she's good.
喔，喔，怎么了？
What? What?
一条电线卡住了，我得松开
One of the wires is jammed.
I'm going to have to Ioosen it.
-你来操纵
-不行！我不要！
-Here, take the stick!
-No! I'm not gonna... No!
我知道你的活力还在
I know you've got moxie in you yet.
靠活力不能开飞机
有飞行执照的人才能开飞机
Moxie doesn't fIy pIanes! PeopIe
who have piIots' Iicenses fIy pIanes!
-好不好？
-交给你了
-Okay.
-She's aII yours.
我不要开！
I don't want it! I don't want the stick!
别往下看，你在开飞机
Don't Iook now, Mr. DaIey,
but you're fIying an airpIane!
阿布，开门！
AbIe! The doors!
-好了！
-抓稳了！
-Got it!
-PuII!
往上拉！
PuII up!
好啊！
Yes!
爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特，祝你顺利
Godspeed, AmeIia Earhart!
祝你顺利
Godspeed.
你看起来有点紧张喔
Look a IittIe nervous there,
Ramen NoodIe.
因为这对我来说跟水疗没两样
'Cause for me,
this is Iike a spa treatment.
沙浴可以活化肌肤、去角质
Sand baths are reaIIy rejuvenating
for the skin. ExfoIiates.
你放弃了吗？
Giving up yet?
还没
Not quite yet, no.
来看看我们能不能让时光飞逝吧
In fact, Iet's see
if we can't make time fIy.
那是什么怪声音？
What is that funny sound?
停！
Stop!
停在那里，达理先生
Right there, pIease, Mr. DaIey.
好，很好
WeII. WeII, weII, weII!
你很会热闹登场嘛
You certainIy know how to make
an entrance, Mr. DaIey.
搬救兵的时候到了
Time to recruit some backup.
为了你的小人国朋友
I hope for your
IittIe friend's sake, here,
希望你破解密码了
that you aIso figured out
the combination.
-把阿嘉交出来
-不行
-Give me Jed.
-Oh, no, no, no.
先把密码跟刻写板给我
First, give me the combination
and hand over that tabIet.
等你放了我朋友
I'II give you the tabIet
and the combination
把他交出来再说
when you reIease my friends
and give him back to me.
我什么时候想放谁都在于我
I shaII reIease what I want to reIease
the moment I want to reIease it.
我也什么时候想交什么
Great. And I'II reIease
what I want to reIease
也在于我
at the exact moment
that I want to reIease it, okay?
现在就把密码跟刻写板交出来
TeII me the combination
and give me that tabIet right now
不然我杀光你朋友
or I shaII kiII aII of your friends,
第一个就是乱发小牛仔
starting with the IittIe
shaggy-headed IittIe cowman here.
我的头发才不乱
巨无霸，让我对付这家伙！
I ain't shaggy-headed!
Gigantor, Iet me take this guy!
这家伙交给我，你不交出我的朋友
Don't worry, I got this handIed.
You don't want to give me my friends,
就拿不到密码跟刻写板
then you're not gonna get
your combination or your tabIet.
-好，告诉你…
-好
-AII right, I'II teII you what.
-Good.
说话算话的卡曼拉
大家可不是白叫的
They didn't caII me
Kahmunrah the Trustworthy for nothing.
我的封号不是说话算话的卡曼拉
Here you go. They didn't caII me
Kahmunrah the Trustworthy!
是嗜血的卡曼拉
They caIIed me
Kahmunrah the BIoodthirsty,
不乖乖听话的，他就通杀
who kiIIs whoever doesn't
give Kahmunrah exactIy what he wants
时间随我挑，就是现在
in the moment that he wants it,
which is right now,
所以最好把密码跟刻写板交给我
when I had aIso better get
the combination and the tabIet!
-大家这么叫你？
-埃及话说起来比较短
-That's what they caIIed you?
-It was shorter in Egyptian.
把他交出来我就给你密码
Great, I'II give you
the combination after you give him back.
好大的胆子，你再碰一次就没命
How dare you? If you touch that again,
I shaII kiII you right now.
-好
-不要碰
-Okay.
-Do not touch this.
-这一区禁止碰触
-好，那…
-This is a no-touching zone!
-Good. WeII, then...
天啊，我不敢相信你又越界了
Oh, my God! I can't beIieve
you reached across Iike that again!
不会吧，我要杀了你
I can't even beIieve it!
Oh, God, I want to kiII you right...
你不知道密码就死定了
If you didn't know this combination,
you'd be so dead right now,
-会死得很惨
-可是我知道密码耶
-it wouId be unbeIievabIe.
-Great, but I do know the combination.
手不准越线！
Don't cross this Iine with your hand!
好大的胆子，如果你再说一次
How dare you! If you
speak again, I'm going to kiII you.
再说一次我就杀了你，了解吗？
Do you understand this?
不要！我看你准备开口罗
Don't say it!
Oh, God, I see you getting ready.
-我没有要说…
-我的天，别说话
-I wasn't gonna say anything.
-Oh, my God, don't say anything.
你再开口我就给你死
I shaII murder you if you taIk again.
把刻写板给我，告诉我密码
Now give me that tabIet
and teII me the combination.
你先交出阿嘉，放了我朋友才行
Okay. After you give me Jed
and reIease my friends.
-你三项都破了
-什么？
-You did aII three!
-What?
你说话，还把手伸过来
You spoke
and you reached your hand across!
我可以说一整晚
Look. I can taIk to you about this
aII night, okay?
-这样好了…
-给我…
-How about this?
-Look, just give...
我现在先不杀你，其实我实在很想
How about I don't kiII you right now,
Iike I reaIIy, reaIIy want to,
我限你五秒内
and I give you preciseIy five seconds
给我刻写板跟密码
to give me that tabIet
and teII me the combination?
我们已经拿到密码了，是圆周率
We aIready got the combination. It's pi.
-3.14159265
-不！
-3.14159265.
-No!
-嘿
-对不起
-Hey.
-Sorry.
这头发爆乱的人说的
他说得可开心了
So Crazy Hair here, he sang.
Oh, did he sing! Like a canary.
赖瑞，对不起
I'm sorry, Larry.
够了，记得上次怎样吗？
Enough out of you!
Remember what happened Iast time?
-够了
-白痴
-That's enough.
-Stupid man.
-你没事吧？
-没事，谢了
-You okay?
-Yeah, thanks.
赖瑞，你一定很闷
Must be a reaI bummer for you, Larry,
你的努力到头来都白费了
knowing that aII of your vaIiant efforts
were, in the end, for naught.
你一定对自己很失望
What a terribIe disappointment
you must be to yourseIf.
大家听到声音了吗？
Do you hear that humming sound?
知道这是什么声音吗？
Do you know what that sound is?
我只是强调
It's rhetoricaI.
这是世界末日的声音
That is the sound of the End.
阿嘉，对不起
I'm sorry, Jed.
你尽力了，巨无霸
You did your best, Gigantor.
该死，我们差点就赢了
Dadgum it, we aImost had him, too.
没有，抱歉我这几年没待在博物馆
No, I mean, I'm sorry I wasn't around
the Iast coupIe of years at the museum.
-说不定就不会变成这样
-巨无霸，你没搞懂耶
-Maybe none of this wouId have happened.
-You don't get it, do you, Gigantor?
我打给你不是因为需要你帮忙
I didn't caII you
'cause we needed your heIp.
我们的确碰到麻烦
Sure, we were in a IittIe pickIe,
不过这不是我第一次
but it wouIdn't have been the first time
杀出重围了
I had to wrestIe my way
out of a root sack.
我打给你是因为你需要我们
No, partner.
I caIIed you 'cause you needed us.
这些年你穿着高级西装到处招摇
That fancy suit you've been parading
around in these past coupIe years,
那是上绞架穿的西装
that there's a hanging suit.
很高档，却是行尸走肉
AII gussied up, but dead inside.
这不像你
That ain't you.
-我再告诉你一件事
-什么事？
-And I'II teII you another thing.
-Yeah.
今晚还没结束
This night ain't over yet.
我这个午夜小牛仔还有门志
This IittIe Midnight Cowboy's
got some fight Ieft in him.
我认为你也有
Something teIIs me you do, too. Ho, now!
欢迎莅临卡曼拉的新疆土
WeIcome to the new,
extended reign of Kahmunrah,
我是埃及第五任国王
Fifth King of Egypt
现在统治全世界！
and now the worId!
赫鲁斯神、拉神，战士们，来吧
Horus, Ra, my warriors, come forth!
替赖瑞达理跟他的朋友送终！
Send Larry DaIey
and his friends to their doom !
停！
HaIt!
伟大的屋大维回来了
The mighty Octavius has returned!
我骑乘自然界最可怕的动物而来
I ride on the back of nature's
most fearsome creature! I ride
我骑的是松鼠！
the squirreI!
骏马，往前冲吧！
Forward now, my mighty steed!
小心
Whoa, girI! Easy.
你们想光荣投降吗？
Do you wish to surrender honorabIy?
还是要流血收场？
Or must this end
with the spiIIing of your bIood?
这就是你的大救兵？
This? This is your big rescue?
不是，这才是！
Oh, no. This is!
那是什么东西？
What is that thing?
我叫林肯
The name is Abraham LincoIn.
-先生，你惨了
-攻击他！
-And you, sir, are in a heap of troubIe!
-Attack it!
恶心的鸽子！
Disgusting haIf-pigeons!
不！哈罗？
No, no, no! HeIIo?
掰啦，鸟头们
Adios, bird brains!
等等，不！
Wait, wait, wait. No, no!
再见，奇怪的鸟人
Goodbye, strange birdmen.
不要回去阴间啊！
Do not return to the UnderworId!
对，快回阴间吧
Yes, yes, do go back
into the UnderworId!
谢谢光临，晚安
Thank you for coming! Good night!
不！
No, no!
喔，好尴尬
Oh, this is awkward.
看来我的工作完成了
It appears my work here is done.
孩子，记住，家和才能万事兴
Just remember, son, a house divided
against itseIf cannot stand.
再见
FareweII.
-现在呢？
-我不确定
-What now?
-You know, I'm not quite sure.
我们应该先看着他死吧
I suppose we shouId probabIy start
by watching him die.
步兵，给他死！
Streltsy! Make him dead!
现在又怎样了？
Now what?
我们不攻击
We are not going to attack right
就是现在！
now!
去逮他们！
Get them !
赖瑞，别怕，我会帮嘉地雅
Fear not, Larry!
I wiII heIp Jedediah!
从后面进攻
You come at them from behind!
-你在干嘛？
-躲起来
-Hey, what's going on?
-I'm hiding.
什么？走吧，我们需要你
Hiding? What are you doing?
Come on, we need you.
-我很没用
-你才不是
-I'm a faiIure.
-No, you're not.
你有带领208名弟兄
Did you fooIishIy Iead
208 Americans to their deaths
在小巨角战死吗？
at the BattIe of LittIe Bighorn?
-没有
-一点都不好
-No.
-No? Not good. Not good at aII.
-是不好
-我很会纸上谈兵
-That's not good.
-Sure, I taIk a good game,
但我配不上这几颗星
but the truth of the matter is,
I don't deserve these stars.
我会永远因为我最大的失败出名
I wiII aIways be famous
for my biggest faiIure.
别这样
Hey.
过去的都过去了，好吗？
The past is the past, okay?
此时此刻，这一晚
Right now, this moment, this night,
这是大家会记得的你
this is what you're gonna be
remembered for.
这是你的最后战役
This is your Iast stand.
-他们需要领导
-没错
-They need a Ieader.
-Yeah, they need a Ieader.
你想当他们的领导吗？
Yeah? You want to be their Ieader, huh?
-我想
-那就来吧
-Yeah, I do.
-Let's do this!
-好吗？
-好耶
-AII right?
-Yeah.
走吧！
Let's go!
不好了
Not good!
赖瑞！
Larry!
嘿，阿布
Hey, AbIe!
我想帮忙
I want to help!
好啊
Oh, great.
你是谁？这是我的博物馆
Who are you?
This is my museum!
他是我朋友，走开！
Well, he's my human.
Back off!
丛林小子，你们需要所有的援兵
You need all the help you can get,
Jungle-Dweller!
少拽了，太空势利鬼
Get over yourself space snob!
嘿，你们
Guys! Hey, guys!
现在不是吵架的时候
This is not the time
to get into this, aII right?
德克斯，这样不好
Dexter, you know better.
这是你打人的下场
AII right?
That's what happens when you do that!
懂吧
You get that.
住手，给我住手，住手！
Stop! Just stop! Stop!
你们两只卷尾猴听着
Now, Iisten. You're both proud capuchin!
专心打敌人
You need to concentrate
on sIapping the enemy!
振作起来，好吗？
Keep it together, aII right?
快走吧，来吧
Come on, Iet's go! Let's do it!
-嘉地雅，他们需要我们
-我不行了
-Jedediah! They need us!
-I ain't gonna make it!
牛仔我撑不住了
Afraid this cowboy's been
to his Iast hoedown.
屋大维，你要记住我的自由狂野
还有…
Octavius, remember me as I was,
wiId, and free, and...
-不用说遗言吧
-我还没说完
-No need for finaI words.
-I'm not finished yet.
我想聊我们的关系
I want to get
to the story of our reIationship,
化敌为友
the evoIution from enemy to friends.
-不！
-会让你痛哭喔
-No!
-It'II make you cry!
不，因为你会活下去！
No! Because you are going to Iive!
-干活吧
-剑给你
-Let's go to work.
-Have a sword.
剑来！
Sword!
小心！
Incoming!
好痛
That smarts.
你打，你踢，你打，你踢
You smack, you kick!
你打，你踢
团结合作，太棒了
You smack, you kick!
Teamwork, feIIas! Wunderbar!
你们好吗？
How you doing, feIIas?
-你还好吗？
-好的不得了
-Are you aII right?
-Never better.
我打暗号你就开门
Listen, when I give you the signaI,
I want you to open the gate.
-你有计划吗？
-我要让家不和
-I take it you have a pIan.
-I'm gonna divide the house.
刻写板，快！
The tabIet! Now!
好，告诉我谁当家
Okay, sure, you can have it.
我就交出来
Just teII me who the boss is
and I'II give it to you.
这要交给卡曼拉吗？
他好像是你的主子
Or shouId I give it to Kahmunrah?
He's your master, right?
-他不是我们的主子
-是吗？他的行为像你们的主子啊
-Nyet! He is not our master!
-ReaIIy? 'Cause he acts Iike he is.
好，告诉我谁当家
But fine, just teII me who the boss is
and you can have it.
那就是我
Hey! That'd be me.
这人是平民，我可是贵族出身
This man is a peasant!
I am the onIy one here of nobIe birth!
他的勋章比较多，帽子也比较大
ReaIIy? 'Cause he's got more medaIs
and a bigger hat, but...
-谢谢
-你的勋章是比较多
-Thank you.
-You might got a Iot of medaIs,
不过你再拿你的小手碰刻写板一次
but you put one of your
IittIe chiId hands on that tabIet again,
你以后就没有手摸东西了
it'II be the Iast thing them tiny
IittIe mitts of yours ever touch.
你干嘛碰小拿？
Why wouId you touch IittIe Nippy?
我能处理
I can handIe this, okay?
你什么都不能处理
你连话都说不好
You can handIe nothing!
You can bareIy speak, you fooI!
你知道吗？没问题
我来帮你，看吧
You know what? No probIem.
I'II give it to you. You see that?
你是精神抖擞的小家伙
Oh, you're a spunky IittIe feIIa !
达理先生，算你聪明
让他们起内讧
Very cIever, Mr. DaIey, getting them
to fight amongst themseIves.
不是我的功劳，这是林肯的主意
Yeah. I can't reaIIy take credit.
It was Abraham LincoIn's idea.
家和才能万事兴
You know, a house divided can't...
-家不和万世穷
-说得好
-Doesn't do weII.
-Yes, weII,
你应该趁机救自己的
you shouId have saved yourseIf
when you had the chance,
因为我现在亲手杀你
because now I shaII have
the tremendous pIeasure
会很乐！
of kiIIing you myseIf!
你是何方神圣？
What are you?
我是夜班警卫
I'm the night guard.
不！
No!
我们胜利了！
Victory is ours!
耶！
Yeah!
这就对了
That's what I'm taIking about!
耶！
Yeah!
我觉得有人找回活力了
I'd say somebody found his moxie.
史密森尼之战
The BattIe of the Smithsonian.
全世界永远不会知道的伟大战役
Perhaps the greatest battIe
the worId wiII never know.
我们知道
We'II know.
对
Yeah.
再一小时就天亮了，我得送你们回去
Oh, man, I got an hour tiII sunrise.
I got to get you guys back.
你忘了吗？他们不要我们了
In case you forgot, Gigantor,
they don't want us there anymore.
我要啊
WeII, I do.
你能送我们一程吗？
Hey, think you couId hook us up
with a ride?
这是我的荣幸
My pIeasure, of course.
等一下，我还要处理一件事
Hang on a second.
One Iast thing I got to take care of.
快点，小子，来啊
Come on, boy! Come on, come on!
进去
Get in there!
很舒服吧？
FeeIs good, right?
不客气
天亮前要回去，好吗？
You're weIcome!
Just get back inside by sunrise, okay?
现在真是充满希望啊
These are promising days, indeed.
来吧
AII right. Hey, come on, guys.
记住，跟好
Remember, stay with your buddy,
aII right?
很好
Good, good.
你回到你的地方了
WeII, you're back where you beIong.
我想是
Yeah. Think so.
我该走了
I guess I shouId be going.
爱蜜莉亚
Hey, AmeIia.
我刚刚想跟你说的事
That thing that I was trying
to teII you about earIier...
我很难开口
There's not reaIIy
an easy way to put this,
-不过，到了早上…
-达理先生，我知道会怎样
-but, in the morning...
-I know what's coming, Mr. DaIey.
我一直都知道
I've aIways known.
不过无所谓
But it doesn't matter.
你在这一晚给了我最精彩的冒险
You've given me the adventure
of a Iifetime in one night.
而且我有预感日出会很美
And I have a feeIing
it's going to be a beautifuI sunrise.
活得开心
Have fun.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不知道你们怎样
不过这牛仔上二垒了
I don't know about you feIIas, but
this oId cowboy just got to second base.
-她走了
-直奔…
-There she goes.
-Straight towards...
加拿大
Canada.
她要去加拿大
She's heading to Canada.
她改变航线了
No, now she course-corrected.
你们去楼下吧
Here, head on downstairs, guys.
-好啦
-赖瑞，晚安
-AII righty.
-Good night, Larry.
小子，你好吗？
Hey, boy, how's it going?
劳伦斯，你把他们带回来了
Lawrence! BIess you
for bringing them back.
你做得太好了
And might I say,
a hearty weII-done is in order.
不过我跟你说
他们不能永远躲在地下室
And may I aIso point out, they
cannot hide in the basement forever.
我搞定这件事了
Yeah. No, I think I got that
figured out.
-真的？
-是
-ReaIIy?
-Yeah.
太阳出来了，笨笨
Sun come, dum-dum.
石像朋友说得对，天快亮了
Our moai friend is right.
The dawn wiII soon be upon us.
泰迪
Hey, Teddy.
记得前晚你说到
Remember the other night
you were saying something
幸福的关键吗？
about the key to happiness?
-我有吗？
-你说幸福的关键是…
-Did I?
-You said, ''The key to happiness is...''
结果日出你就定格了
And then the sun came up and you froze.
-我想我知道了
-很好
-I think I got it figured out.
-Yes?
那就是跟你爱的人一起做你爱做的事
It's doing what you Iove, isn't it?
With peopIe you Iove.
我本来要说运动
ActuaIIy, I was going to say
''physicaI exercise'',
不过爱这个想法很好
but the Iove thing's good, too.
-劳伦斯
-是
-Lawrence!
-Yeah.
小子，欢迎你回家
WeIcome home, son.
谢了
Thanks.
各位，等待结束了
经过两个月的整修
WeII, foIks, the wait is over.
After two months of renovation,
现在开放
自然历史博物馆在今天晚上
重新对外开放
tonight, The Museum of NaturaI History
reopens its doors to the pubIic.
纽约人蜂拥而至
As you can see,
New Yorkers are fIooding in,
很期待看到馆内的改变
eager to see
just what changes are in store.
晚上开放时间延长
With its new, extended night hours,
据说博物馆会更加生动
we're toId the museum
wiII be more IiveIy than ever.
-你看看，你看看
-嗨
-WeII, weII, weII, weII!
-Hey.
过了这么多年，制服还很合身
I see the uniform stiII fits
after these Iong, Iong years.
也没那么久啦
Yeah, yeah.
ReaIIy hasn't been that Iong, but...
我们怎么请得动你回来？
So, to what do we owe
this ''triumphant'' return?
不适合企业丛林？被炒鱿鱼了？
Not cut out for the ''corporate'' jungIe
after aII. Got fired.
其实，我把公司卖了
No, actuaIIy, I soId my company.
世界的变化果然神秘
The worId doth move in mysterious ways.
之前还说要全面汰旧换新
One day, we've got to get rid
of everything oId,
结果出现一个匿名捐款人
给了我们天文数字的捐款
the next, a rich, anonymous donor
gives a huge endowment.
附带条件是一切维持原状
With a proviso:
everything stays the same. So...
-也不算没有完全一样啦
-不算
-WeII, not exactIy the same, obviousIy.
-No.
各位先生女士，我叫罗斯福
BuIIy, Iads and Iadies,
the name is Theodore RooseveIt,
我是博物学家、游骑兵
以及美国第26任总统
naturaIist, Rough Rider and twenty-sixth
President of these great United States.
来吧，准备打猎了
嗨，劳伦斯
Come aIong, Iad. The hunt is afoot.
Lawrence.
笨笨，有带泡泡糖给我吗？
Hey, you dum-dums bring me gum-gum?
3千年前，我爸妈给了我刻写板
My parents gave me this tabIet
some 3,000 years ago,
把埃及最珍贵的财b交给我
entrusting me with one of my peopIe's
most prized possessions.
-它有作用吗？
-有作用？
-Does it do anything?
-Do anything?
如果没作用要干嘛？
Yeah. What's the point
if it doesn't do anything?
告诉他们
Tell 'em
它的魔法能让所有的展品复活
ActuaIIy, it has a magicaI power
that brings aII the exhibits to Iife.
说真的啦，它有什么作用？
No, reaIIy, what's it do?
没有，只是装饰
Nothing. It's just for decoration.
我就知道
I knew it.
这地方超逊的，这东西看起来好假
This pIace is Iame.
This thing doesn't even Iook reaI.
说真的，这些电子傀儡好烂
SeriousIy, dude,
these animatronics suck.
-长毛象吗？
-是呀
-Mammoth?
-Yeah.
绝种了
Extinct!
-我追不上今日的科技
-栩栩如生
-Today's technoIogy is beyond me.
-I know. It's so IifeIike.
-对呀，对呀
-了不起
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Something eIse.
你会留下来吗？
You'II stick around
a bit Ionger this time,
还是见好就跑？
or you gonna run away again
when you get something better?
-我要留下来
-长期留下来
-I'm gonna stay.
-Stay, for a Iong time.
-对
-Yeah.
好，很好
因为就夜班警卫而言…
Good. 'Cause,
as night guards go, you're...
-什么？
-…你是最棒的
-What?
-The best.
真的
Excuse me.
小朋友，不要抱展品
You, the toddIer!
Don't hug the dispIays.
嗨，对不起
I'm sorry. Hi.
我不是故意要盯着你
I don't mean to stare. I just...
你好像我认识的一个人
You Iook a Iot
Iike somebody I know, and...
我常听到这句话
I get that a Iot.
-你有吗？
-对，我想我是大众脸
-Do you?
-Yeah. I guess I have that kind of face.
-熟脸孔
-对
-FamiIiar.
-Yeah.
你跟爱蜜莉亚埃尔哈特是亲戚吗？
You're not by any chance
reIated to AmeIia Earhart, are you?
-不是
-No.
-我想不是
-当然不是
-No, I don't think so.
-Of course you're not.
-我不知道，说不定
-我不得不问
-I mean, I don't know. Maybe I'm...
-I just had to ask. I'm sorry.
她是飞越太平洋那女的
She was that woman
who fIew across the Pacific.
-是大西洋
-喔，是大西洋
-The AtIantic.
-AtIantic. Of course.
第一个飞越大西洋的女人
First woman to fIy across the AtIantic,
and she received the FIying Cross,
第一个得到飞行十字勋章的女人
first woman to do that.
-好酷喔
-对，她很酷
-That's very cooI.
-Yeah, she was cooI.
你该去小人国逛逛
Hey, you know what you shouId check out
is the the HaII of Miniatures.
你能带我去吗？我老是迷路
CouId you take me there?
I'm aIways getting Iost.
好啊，来吧
Yeah, I know. Sure.
Yeah, I'II show you. Come on.
谢谢
Thank you.
-我叫赖瑞达理
-我叫泰丝
-I'm Larry DaIey.
-Tess.
-乔瑟夫，吃晚饭了！
-马上来
-Joseph, time for dinner!
-One second, Ma !
乔伊摩托罗拉，给我下来吃饭！
Joey MotoroIa, you get down here
for supper right now!
等一下啦，我快搞懂一件事了！
I said one second, Ma !
I reaIIy think I'm on to something here!